ABHINAV MISHRA

52 Calumet St Apt 2, Boston, MA,

02120 • 8573179611 • abhinav m@hotmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/amishra93/

Summary

Software Engineer with over 5 years of work experience across various technical domains such Full Stack and Frontend, Business Intelligence, and Data Analytics. Some of the technologies I have experience in are JavaScript, Python, Java, SQL, MongoDB, Golang and TypeScript.

Technical Skills

- Languages and Frameworks: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, React.js, Golang, Java, Node.js, HTML, CSS, SQL.
- Databases and Software Tools:Docker, Kubernetes, PostGRESQL, MySQL, Neo4J, MongoDB, GIT, SVN and JIRA.

Experience

Software Engineer Intern

June 2022 - December 2022

Snowflake, San Mateo CA, USA

- Led efforts on the App Foundation team to limit client-side customer sensitive information logging, reducing same by over 75%. Tech Stack: Golang, TypeScript, React.js, Java, PostGRESQL.
- Implemented a new telemetry system across the UI and backend APIS in Golang and Java to give fine grained and granular understanding about Critical user journeys improving telemetry logging by > 50%.
- Built Dashboards and alerts using Snowflake, monitoring live feature deployment pipelines giving an immediate (0 second response time) to client facing errors.

Web Developer M1

January 2019 - June 2021

TIMES INTERNET, Noida, India

- Architected and engineered a Progressive Web App solution for mobile serving users across 8 different languages, having a peak of 500,000 concurrent users, leveraging React.js and Node.js.
- Achieved an increase ad revenue by 20% and decrease in page load time by 25%. PWA solution for mobile achieved 100/100 on all performance aspects and won a presentation spot at Google I/O.
- Redesigned logging for web application deployment infrastructure through scripts written in Python and bash, achieving fault notification time improvements by more than 50%.

Frontend Engineer

April 2018 - September 2018

BUDDY4STUDY, Noida, India

- Pivoted existing web application technological stack from jQuery and Php to React.js, D3.js, Python and Django enhancing performance on critical areas such as SEO and page load time by up to 15%.
- Improved page ranking and SEO of web application, for keywords of "Education and Scholarship" related searches to be in top 10 results by implementing Server Side Rendering using Python and Django.

Software Engineer

September 2015 - June 2017

TECTURA INFOTECH, Noida, India

• Generated reports in MS Dynamics AX and MSBI for clients, analyzing and consolidating sales, invoice and inventory related data from MSSQL database through visualizations and reports using C# and MSSQL.

Education

Master of Science, Data Analytics Engineering

Northeastern University, Boston, MA - GPA 4.0 / 4.0

Expected December 2023

Relevant Coursework: Distributed Systems, Data Mining, Machine Learning, Database Management.

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science Engineering

Amity University, Noida, India

May 2015

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures, Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming, Design Patterns.